A Guide to the W. W. LaPrade and Brothers Records, 1803-2001 (bulk 1900-1970)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
W. W. LaPrade and Brothers Records, 1803-2001 (bulk 1900-1970)
The Library of Virginia
40031, 43183
cu. ft. (381+ boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Foster and Miller, Glen Allen, Virginia, August 2002 (Acc. 40031).
Gift of Foster and Miller, Glen Allen, Virginia, April 2007 (Acc. 43183).
Gift of Mrs. Newlon, Richmond, Virginia, April 2009 (Acc. 44221). Additional Thornton Mullins records.
Biographical Information
The LaPrade family were long time residents of Chesterfield County and served for many years as county surveyors. William LaPrade (1767-1817) was appointed Chesterfield County surveyor in 1801, serving until his death in 1817 when his son, David LaPrade (b. 1799) became surveyor. The job passed on to David's son, Joseph Edgar (1845-1903), and then to Joseph Edgar's sons, David Flournoy (1872-1955), Joseph E. (1876-1945), William Waverly (1878-1952) and Benjamin Watkins (1885-1965). Around 1912 the brothers Benjamin W., Joseph E., and William W. formed the partnership of W. W. LaPrade and Brothers.
David Flournoy LaPrade (1872-1955) was married to Grace Eva Moseley (b. 1877) and had five children: Grace Agnes (b. 1905), David Flournoy (b. 1907), Nettie Mildred, Edmond Moseley (b. 1911), and Ann Augusta. He served as the city engineer for Manchester and later Richmond, when the city was annexed in 1910, until his retirement in 1951.
Benjamin W. LaPrade attended Virginia Polytechnic Institute, graduating in 1909 with a degree in electrical engineering. In March 1912 he joined his father's firm in partnership with his brothers, William Waverly and Joseph. He married Francis Elizabeth James (b. 1889) 30 August 1917 in Washington, D.C. From 1917 to 1919 he served as a captain with the Army Corps of Engineering in Panama, returning to LaPrade after the war. In 1955 C. R. Johnson and C.A. Watkins Jr. became partners in the company, along with Joseph LaPrade Jr. and a grand-nephew David.
William Waverly LaPrade attended Virginia Military Institute, graduating in 1904. He continued to remain at VPI to teach math until 1907 when he started work the family surveying company of LaPrade. In 1920 he married Evelyn Byrd Warwick. After World War I, he served with the Quartermaster Corps, Virginia National Guard. In 1940 he was assigned to duty as state procurement officer and retired with the rank of general in 1946.
Scope and Content
Records, 1803-2001 (bulk 1900-1970) of W. W. LaPrade and Brothers, certified engineers and surveyors in Chesterfield County, Virginia. The company surveyed land mainly in Chesterfield and Henrico Counties and Richmond, Virginia, although many other Virginia counties are also included. The collection consists of computation books, field books and diaries, and plats and surveys prepared by LaPrade for various companies and land owners.
Series I-V: The bulk of the collection are the plats and property surveys (single, multi-lots, and subdivisions) and consist mostly of mid to late twentieth century material, although throughout the collection a small number of nineteenth century surveys can be found. The collection was housed in either filing cabinets (Vertical files Series I-IV) or map cases (Oversize surveys Series V) and was maintained in its original order. Because of the nature in which the records were kept the researcher must consult BOTH the Vertical files and the Oversize surveys series to find all LaPrade records for any specific location. There is much overlap between these two main series. The collection is not organized chronologically so researchers looking for a specific survey must look in all boxes relating to the specific County and District.
To access the Vertical files series, LaPrade Brothers maintained Index Keys for Chesterfield and Henrico Counties (by magisterial district) and Richmond, Virginia (by district imposed by LaPrade). Chesterfield County districts include Bermuda (map 8), Clover Hill (map 6), Dale (map 7), Manchester (map 10), Matoaca (map 5), and Midlothian (map 9). Henrico County districts include Brookland, Fairfield, Three Chopt, Tuckahoe, and Varina (maps 3 and 4). Richmond is categorized by districts imposed by LaPrade (maps 11 and 12). Researchers must know the County and District for the specific area they are researching. [The Index Keys (maps) can be viewed online at the Library of Virginia's website.] Once the researcher knows the County and District, they must consult the LaPrade Index Keys for that County and District. Each District has been further subdivided by a file numbering system created by the company (i.e. Henrico County, Varina District 2 or Richmond H-22). Researchers must find the specific street area on the Index Key to locate the file number. Once the file number has been obtained the researcher can consult the Vertical series (Boxes 1-43). The Other Counties and Cities Vertical files series do not have index keys and are arranged alphabetically county and then within by folder title.
Similarly the Oversize survey series (Boxes 67-175) is arranged by County and District although it is not further subdivided by Index Keys like the Vertical files series. Researchers only need to know the County and District (or Richmond) to view these records. Because many boxes may exist for a certain County and District, researchers might need to consult several boxes to find materials.
Due to redistricting many of the locations have changed districts, therefore researchers might have to look in several boxes to find all surveys pertaining to a district. Noted in the container listing is not only the current district name but also former ones. For example the container listing might note Chesterfield County, Dale district (also includes former Bermuda, Manchester, and Matoaca districts). The container listing may also include the folder title or a more detailed description of surveys located in the box. Due to the size of the collection an itemized listing of each plat was not possible, but an attempt was made to include some detailed information in the container listing. Index cards are available for some of the Chesterfield County Midlothian districts and also the Miscellaneous files (Misc. 10, 11, 11-2, 12). Some of the files were labeled for example, Clover Hill 8 or Dale Big 6. It is unknown what these mean.
Series VI- IX: Include the files of Ernest W. Brooks, Foster and Miller, Thornton L. Mullins, and Carl Watkins, surveyors who either worked for or their files were obtained by LaPrade. The bulk of the plats and surveys were for land in Chesterfield and Henrico Counties and Richmond. The largest series are the files of Ernest W. Brooks and consists of 7 boxes of plats and surveys of Chesterfield, Hanover, and Henrico Counties and Richmond, Virginia. Also included are a small number of plats for land in Amelia, Caroline, Charles City, Essex, Gloucester, Goochland, King and Queen, New Kent, Powhatan, and York Counties. The Oversize Series (Series V) also includes surveys of Ernest W. Brooks and W. S. Hinton (boxes 93-95). The files of Carl Watkins contain clippings, brochures, newsletters, and reports on a variety of subjects. These files do not contain any plats or surveys. All the records were maintained in their original order.
Series X-XII: Includes field books/diaries, computation books, and volumes. The field books and diaries contain the raw field data and sketches that were used to create the plats and surveys. The computation books contain the surveyors' mathematical calculations for jobs using data that they gathered in the field books. Also included are three plat books created by LaPrade.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Chesterfield County Vertical files
Series II: Henrico County Vertical files
Series III: Richmond Vertical files
Series IV: Other Counties and Cities Vertical files
Series V: Oversize Surveys
Series VI: Ernest W. Brooks Vertical files
Series VII: Foster and Miller Vertical files
Series VIII: Thornton L. Mullins Vertical files
Series IX: Carl Watkins Vertical files
Series X: Field Books/Diaries
Series XI: Computation Books
Series XII: Volumes
Contents List
- Series I: Chesterfield County Vertical files, 1844-2001 (bulk 1940-1970)., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  This series includes plats and surveys, correspondence and deeds, relating to Chesterfield County. The more recent files, ca. 1980-1990, also include site plan applications, newspaper clippings, utility, sewer, and topographical maps, memos, soil evaluation reports, and building ordinances relating to the properties.
  Arranged alphabetically by district and within each district arranged numerically. The numbering system directly relates to the Index Keys created by LaPrade. Consult the Keys to figure out the correlating number for the district. The collection is not organized chronologically so researchers looking for a specific survey must look in ALL boxes relating to the specific county and district.
  - Subseries 1. Bermuda District., 1 box (1 cu. ft.)
    - Bermuda 1. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bermuda 1. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Falling Creek Hills, Bensley
    - Bermuda 2. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bermuda 3. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bermuda 3-1. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Mr. L.R. Goyne (now Libby)
    - Bermuda 4. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bermuda 5. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bermuda 5-1. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bermuda 6. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bermuda 6. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      John Markum
    - Bermuda 7. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bermuda 7. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Edward, Milton, and Thomas Friend
    - Bermuda 8. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      James B. Friend, J.W. Miles, Maria F. Thompson, Aaron Prue, Joseph H. Booker
    - Bermuda 8. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Reynolds Metals Co., Reymet Rd.
    - Bermuda 9. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bermuda 9. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Sarah Sinclair estate, Rt. 616
    - Bermuda 10. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bermuda 11. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bermuda 12. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bermuda 13. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bermuda 14. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bermuda 14. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      William D. Maxey
    - Bermuda 14. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Point of Rocks Park, Enon Church Rd. Also Cameron Farms
    - Bermuda 15. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bermuda 15-1. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bermuda 16. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bermuda 17. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bermuda 18. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bermuda 19. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bermuda 19. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Hidden Valley Estates subdivision
    - Bermuda 20. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bermuda 21. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bermuda 21. (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Lakewood Farms
    - Bermuda 21. (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Allen Woodfin
    - Bermuda 22. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bermuda 22-2. (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Lora Lynn Heights
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Buckhead Springs
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Fannie W. Shield
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Fan Court
    - Bermuda 23. (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Trueheart Heights
    - Bermuda 23-A. (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Schools and Carter
    - Bermuda 23-1. (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Shady Springs, Deford Tract
    - Bermuda 24. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bermuda miscellaneous (1818-1913). (Box 1, Folder 45a)
    - Bermuda miscellaneous, Port Walthall (1808-1924). (Box 1, Folder 45b)
    - Bermuda miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Roads in Bermuda district
    - Bermuda miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 47-52)
      DuPont slurry pipe line
    - Bermuda miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Willis Rd. pumping station
  - Subseries 2. Clover Hill District., 1/2 box (.45 cu. ft.)
    - Clover Hill 1. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Clover Hill 2. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Clover Hill 2. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Henry L. Gill
    - Clover Hill 3. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Clover Hill 4. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Clover Hill 5. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clover Hill 5. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      George T. Martin, Neta Eudailey
    - Clover Hill 6. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Clover Hill 7. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Clover Hill 7. (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Frank Flournoy tract
    - Clover Hill 8. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Clover Hill 8. (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Bethia Methodist Church and Union Chapel (1822-1902, 1959-1979)
    - Clover Hill 8. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Alfred Cheatham
    - Clover Hill 9. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Clover Hill 9. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      later Matoaca District (1989); Mrs. Dorothy Franklin (Spring Run Rd.)
    - Clover Hill 9. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      later Matoaca District (1997); Vernelle Spiers; Helena Spiers Avery; Edgar L. Awalt
    - Clover Hill 9. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      later Matoaca District (1994); M.J. Rapalee
    - Clover Hill 9. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Spiers and Avery
    - Clover Hill 10. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Clover Hill 11. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      later Matoaca District (1997); Glenna L. Norvell estate
    - Clover Hill 11. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Clover Hill 12. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Clover Hill 13. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Clover Hill 14. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Clover Hill miscellaneous (1821-1922). (Box 2, Folder 24a)
    - Clover Hill miscellaneous, Hebron (1830-1910). (Box 2, Folder 24b)
    - Clover Hill miscellaneous, Skinquarter (1824-1907). (Box 2, Folder 24c)
    - Clover Hill miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
      LaPrade library; Bexley subdivision (see also Manchester 29 for additional Bexley materials)
    - Clover Hill miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 26a)
      Water supply reservoirs, various properties.
  - Subseries 3. Dale District., 1 box (1 cu. ft.)
    - Dale 1-A. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Dale 1-B. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Dale 2. (Box 2, Folder 28a-28c)
    - Dale 3-A. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dale 3-B. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Dale 3-B. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Satinwood Dr.
    - Dale 3-C. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Dale 3-C. (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Julian and Mary Stratton
    - Dale 3-C. (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Gwendolyn C. Thomas
    - Dale 4. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Dale 6. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Dale 6. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Dale 6. (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Archer estate
    - Dale 6. (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Meadowood
    - Dale 6. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Dale 7. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Dale 8. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Dale 8. (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Brittonwood
    - Dale 8. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Dale 9. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Dale 9. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Dale 9-A. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dale 9-A. (Box 3, Folder 1a)
    - Dale 10. (Box 3, Folder 1b)
    - Dale 10. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Hollyberry Hills (Harold Taylor)
    - Dale 10. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      B.O. Woodcock; Sewage Treatment Plant
    - Dale 11. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dale 12. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Dale 13. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Dale 14. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Dale 15. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dale 16. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Dale 17. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dale 17. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Qualla Farms
    - Dale 18. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Dale 19. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dale miscellaneous (1831-1923). (Box 3, Folder 13a)
    - Dale miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Strathmore road extension
  - Subseries 4. Manchester District., 2.5 boxes (2.5 cu. ft.)
    - Manchester 1. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Manchester 5. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      DuPont
    - Manchester 6. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Manchester 8. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Manchester 9. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Manchester 11. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Manchester 11-A. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Manchester 11-B. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Manchester 11-C. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Manchester 11-1. (Box 3, Folder 24)
      McGuire Village
    - Manchester 12. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Manchester 13. (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Henley property, now in Richmond city
    - Manchester 13. (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Shackelford
    - Manchester 13. (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Walmsley Village
    - Manchester 13. (Box 3, Folder 28a-b)
      P.C. Warwick property of Campfield
    - Manchester 13-A. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Manchester 13-B. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Manchester 13-B. (Box 3, Folder 30a)
      Cherry Gardens
    - Manchester 13-B. (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Twyman Terrace
    - Manchester 13-1. (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Rolando
    - Manchester 13-1-A. (Box 3, Folder 32a-b)
    - Manchester 13-2. (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Rennolds and Williams; Cardwell
    - Manchester 14. (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Grant Lake Hills
    - Manchester 14-A. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Manchester 14-A1. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Manchester 14-A2. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Manchester 14-B. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Manchester 14-D. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Manchester 14-E. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Manchester 14-E. (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Edward Nunnally
    - Manchester 15-A. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Manchester 15-B. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Manchester 15-C. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Manchester 15-C. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Manchester 16-A. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Manchester 16-A. (Box 3, Folder 47)
      W.L. Worsham; US# 360 west of Warwick
    - Manchester 16-B. (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Delta Heights
    - Manchester 16-B. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Manchester 16-C. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Manchester 16-D. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Manchester 16-D. (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Chippenham Place Apts. road extension
    - Manchester 16-E. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Manchester 17. (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Broad Rock Heights and home sites
    - Manchester 17-A. (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Cranford Heights
    - Manchester 17-A. (Box 3, Folder 55a)
      Village Square Apartments
    - Manchester 17-B. (Box 3, Folder 56)
      James S. Stanley property
    - Manchester 17-B. (Box 3, Folder 57)
      Woodstock
    - Manchester 17-B1. (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Southside Plaza Shopping Center
    - Manchester 17-C. (Box 3, Folder 59)
      Belt Boulevard from Hull St. to Midlothian Turnpike
    - Manchester 17-C. (Box 3, Folder 60)
      McGuire Circle Shopping Center
    - Manchester 17-C1 - 17-D. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Manchester 17-E. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Manchester 17-E. (Box 3, Folder 63)
      Wallace LaPrade; Route #60
    - Manchester 17-E. (Box 3, Folder 64)
      Somers Wilton
    - Manchester 17-F. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Manchester 17-F. (Box 3, Folder 66)
      Cavalier Court
    - Manchester 18-A. (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Manchester 18-A. (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Bolton Manor Lowell Smith property on Swanson Rd.
    - Manchester 18-A. (Box 3, Folder 69)
      Future Church of Christ 5545 Warwick
    - Manchester 18-B. (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Manchester 18-B. (Box 3, Folder 71)
      Stuart Cordle, Swanson Rd.
    - Manchester 18-C. (Box 3, Folder 72)
      See also 18-A
    - Manchester 18-D. (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Manchester 18-D. (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Adams Heating/AC
    - Manchester 19-A. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Manchester 19-A. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Exeter Meadows
    - Manchester 19-B. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Manchester 19-C. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Manchester 19-D. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Manchester 19-D1. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Westover Manor
    - Manchester 19-1. (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Norwood Park
    - Manchester 19-2. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Manchester 20-A. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Forest View Heights
    - Manchester 20-A. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Manchester 20-A1. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Raleigh Court
    - Manchester 20-B. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Manchester 21-A. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Manchester 21-A1. (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Clevedon; H.S. Realty
    - Manchester 21-B. (Box 4, Folder 15)
      City
    - Manchester 21-B. (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Stratford Hills
    - Manchester 22-A. (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Wooldridge family
    - Manchester 22-B. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Manchester 22-B. (Box 4, Folder 18a)
    - Manchester 22-B. (Box 4, Folder 18b)
      Part of Wilson Howlett and others
    - Manchester 22-B. (Box 4, Folder 18c)
    - Manchester 23-A. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Manchester 23-A. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Manchester 23-B. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Beaufont Oaks-Beaufont Towers retirement home
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Chinaberry Square
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Now Midlothian district
    - Manchester 24. (Box 4, Folder 27)
      Now City- annexed 1970; Cloverdale, Highland Manor, Shell Oil Co.
    - Manchester 24-A. (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Glen Echo Place
    - Manchester 25-A. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Manchester 25-B. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Manchester 25-B. (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Annexed by city 1970
    - Manchester 25-B. (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Arlen Shopping Center
    - Manchester 25-B. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Cloverleaf Mall
    - Manchester 26-A. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Manchester 26-B. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Manchester 26-B. (Box 4, Folder 36)
      Now Clover Hill District
    - Manchester 26-B1. (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Manchester Lake Property
    - Manchester 26-C. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Manchester 26-C. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Manchester 26-C. (Box 4, Folder 40)
      Elkhardt Middle School
    - Manchester 27-A. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Manchester 27-B. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Manchester 27-B. (Box 4, Folder 43)
      Arby's Hull St. Rd.; Clover Hill District
    - Manchester 27-C. (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Manchester 28. (Box 4, Folder 45)
      Linwood G. Weisiger
    - Manchester 28-A. (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Manchester 28-A. (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Hancock and Fred Barber; Wamsley Blvd.
    - Manchester 28-B. (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Manchester 28-C. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Manchester 29. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Manchester 29. (Box 5, Folder 2-17)
      Bexley, Bexley Dams, Bexley Outpost (see also Clover Hill miscellaneous for additional Bexley. In both Chesterfield County, Clover Hill and Manchester districts)
    - Manchester 29. (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Annie Bell Williams Crump
    - Manchester 29. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Wallace LaPrade Properties; Lake George Hamlet
    - Manchester 29. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Loch Braemar
    - Manchester 29. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Miscellaneous
    - Manchester miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 3a)
      Stuart S. Cordle Mobile Home Park
    - Manchester miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 3b)
      Dutch Village
    - Manchester miscellaneous (1830-1926). (Box 6, Folder 3c)
      Wintree Stone
    - Manchester miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 3d)
      Yardley Square Apartments
  - Subseries 5. Matoaca District., 1/2 box (.5 cu. ft.)
    - Matoaca 1. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Benton B. Mann; Barbara and Paul Plunkett
    - Matoaca 1. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Matoaca 2. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Matoaca 3. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Matoaca 7. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Matoaca 7. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Beverly Acres
    - Matoaca 9. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Matoaca 9. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Nations Bank of Virginia, Louise B. Kafka land
    - Matoaca 10. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Matoaca 11. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Matoaca 11. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      College Park
    - Matoaca 11. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Southside Builders Inc.
    - Matoaca 12. (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Colonial Heights
    - Matoaca 12. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Matoaca miscellaneous (1820-1912). (Box 6, Folder 17a)
  - Subseries 6. Midlothian District., 1 box (1 cu. ft.)
    - Midlothian 1. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Midlothian 1. (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Oxford addition
    - Midlothian 1. (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Weston
    - Midlothian 2. (Box 6, Folder 21)